<root>
<software>
<name name="AutoTract" nitrc="https://www.nitrc.org/projects/autotract" />
<description> AutoTract is an automatic tractography tool featuring advanced processing tools to clean tracts after the initial tractography. It uses the Slicer TractographyLabelMapSeeding, with tracts from a reference DTI atlas as label maps. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The 3 main steps of the tool are:&lt;br /&gt;-Registration between the DTI image that we want to tract and the reference DTI atlas.&lt;br /&gt;-Tractography of the DTI image using the TractographyLabelMapSeeding Slicer module.&lt;br /&gt;-Process of each tract individually to clean and remove any unwanted fiber.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The processing includes (for each tract): &lt;br /&gt;-cutting every fiber ends that are in the gray matter (cutting them until the fiber ends is in the white matter), based on a white matter mask created by the tool.&lt;br /&gt;-ensuring every fiber is not in the CSF (removes them from the tract otherwise)&lt;br /&gt;-several image comparisons with the reference tracts (such as fiber length matching, use of a distance map to ensure that the tract is close to the reference tract, and potentially to be added later on, shape comparison). 
&lt;p/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nitrc.org/project/screenshot.php?group_id=948&amp;screenshot_id=935&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1824&quot; src=&quot;https://www.nitrc.org/project/screenshot.php?group_id=948&amp;screenshot_id=935&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;458&quot; height=&quot;248&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</description>
<license>Apache License 2.0</license>
<category>Diffusion MR Fiber Tracking</category>
<platform>MacOS</platform>
<platform>Linux</platform>
<input>Nrrd</input>
<output>Nrrd</output>
<release>Jun 16, 2015</release>
<homepage>http://www.nitrc.org/projects/autotract/</homepage>
<maintainer>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (UNC-CH)</maintainer>
<HBP>External</HBP>
<deployment>Standalone</deployment>
<display>Desktop</display>
</software>
</root>